<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>Milestone 5. Fees and Price Oracle on Uniswap V3 Development Book</title><link>https://uniswapv3book.com/docs/milestone_5/</link><description>Recent content in Milestone 5. Fees and Price Oracle on Uniswap V3 Development Book</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><language>en-us</language><atom:link href="https://uniswapv3book.com/docs/milestone_5/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>Introduction</title><link>https://uniswapv3book.com/docs/milestone_5/introduction/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://uniswapv3book.com/docs/milestone_5/introduction/</guid><description>Fees and Price Oracle # In this milestone, we&amp;rsquo;re going to add two new features to our Uniswap implementation. They share one similarity: they work on top of what we have already built–that&amp;rsquo;s why we&amp;rsquo;ve delayed them until this milestone. However, they&amp;rsquo;re not equally important.
We&amp;rsquo;re going to add swap fees and a price oracle:
Swap fees is a crucial mechanism of the DEX design we&amp;rsquo;re implementing. They&amp;rsquo;re the glue that makes things stick together.</description></item><item><title>Swap Fees</title><link>https://uniswapv3book.com/docs/milestone_5/swap-fees/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://uniswapv3book.com/docs/milestone_5/swap-fees/</guid><description>Swap Fees # As I mentioned in the introduction, swap fees is a core mechanism of Uniswap. Liquidity providers need to get paid for the liquidity they provide, otherwise they&amp;rsquo;ll just use it somewhere else. To incentivize them, trades pay a small fee during each swap. These fees then distributed among all liquidity providers pro rata (proportionally to their share in total pool liquidity).
To better understand the mechanism of fees collection and distribution, let&amp;rsquo;s see how they work.</description></item><item><title>Flash Loan Fees</title><link>https://uniswapv3book.com/docs/milestone_5/flash-loan-fees/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://uniswapv3book.com/docs/milestone_5/flash-loan-fees/</guid><description>Flash Loan Fees # In a previous chapter we implemented flash loans and made them free. However, Uniswap collects swap fees on flash loans, and we&amp;rsquo;re going to add this to our implementation: the amounts repaid by flash loan borrowers must include a fee.
Here&amp;rsquo;s what the updated flash function looks like:
function flash( uint256 amount0, uint256 amount1, bytes calldata data ) public { uint256 fee0 = Math.</description></item><item><title>Protocol Fees</title><link>https://uniswapv3book.com/docs/milestone_5/protocol-fees/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://uniswapv3book.com/docs/milestone_5/protocol-fees/</guid><description>Protocol Fees # While working on the Uniswap implementation, you&amp;rsquo;ve probably asked yourself, &amp;ldquo;How does Uniswap make money?&amp;rdquo; Well, it doesn&amp;rsquo;t (at least as of September 2022).
In the implementation we&amp;rsquo;ve built so far, traders pay liquidity providers for providing liquidity, and Uniswap Labs, as the company that developed the DEX, is not part of this process. Neither traders, nor liquidity providers pay Uniswap Labs for using the Uniswap DEX.</description></item><item><title>Price Oracle</title><link>https://uniswapv3book.com/docs/milestone_5/price-oracle/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://uniswapv3book.com/docs/milestone_5/price-oracle/</guid><description>Price Oracle # The final mechanism we&amp;rsquo;re going to add to our DEX is a price oracle. Even though it&amp;rsquo;s not essential to a DEX (there are DEXes that don&amp;rsquo;t implement a price oracle), it&amp;rsquo;s still an important feature of Uniswap and something that&amp;rsquo;s interesting to learn about.
What is Price Oracle? # Price oracle is a mechanism that provides asset prices to blockchain. Since blockchains are isolated ecosystems, there&amp;rsquo;s no direct way of querying external data, e.</description></item><item><title>User Interface</title><link>https://uniswapv3book.com/docs/milestone_5/user-interface/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://uniswapv3book.com/docs/milestone_5/user-interface/</guid><description>User Interface # In this milestone, we&amp;rsquo;ve added the ability to remove liquidity from a pool and collect accumulated fees. Thus, we need to reflect these changes in the user interface to allow users to remove liquidity.
Fetching Positions # To let user choose how much liquidity to remove, we first need to fetch user&amp;rsquo;s positions from a pool. To makes this easier, we can add a helper function to the Manager contract, which will return user position in a specific pool:</description></item></channel></rss>